{
    "id": "7a2afd4064044ca3bb7d58d4bc913f89",
    "title": "Gap Fills Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "In case you …………………………… John, tell him that he still owes me a drink.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "see",
                "will see"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "You never say what you are thinking, ……………………………….?",
            "description": "Non-negative tags are used after words like never, no, nobody etc.",
            "answers": [
                "do you",
                "don't you"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I ………………………………. beach holidays.",
            "description": "In the simple present tense, questions and negatives are made with do.",
            "answers": [
                "like not",
                "do not like"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Did you …………………………….. swimming yesterday?",
            "description": "After do, does and did, we use the infinitive without to.",
            "answers": [
                "go",
                "gone",
                "went"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "We need to know ……………………………… he is coming tomorrow.",
            "description": "Whether is a question word used in indirect questions.",
            "answers": [
                "whether",
                "that"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I promise I …………………………….. any more.",
            "description": "We do not normally use the simple present to talk about the future.",
            "answers": [
                "don't smoke",
                "won't smoke"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "I …………………………… my new job tomorrow.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to refer to future events which are timetabled.",
            "answers": [
                "start",
                "will start",
                "starts"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I wasn’t …………………………… that she was there.",
            "description": "Prepositions are not used before that.",
            "answers": [
                "aware",
                "aware of"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "I was surprised …………………………… his strength.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "by",
                "at",
                "with"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The virus ……………………………….. thousands of people across the world.",
            "description": "The present perfect is used to give news.",
            "answers": [
                "killed",
                "has killed"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The portrait …………………………….. by a famous artist.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "painted",
                "was painted",
                "has painted"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "Aren’t you interested ……………………………… what happened to him?",
            "description": "Interested can be followed by an -ing form or infinitive. This is common when we are talking about a wish to find out something.",
            "answers": [
                "in knowing",
                "to know",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}